Dzmitry Predkel

dpredkel@gmail.com | +48 790 536 079 | LinkedIn | GitHub

EXPERIENCE

GOOGLE | SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Aug 2023 - Present | Poland (EU)

- Led the EU legislation compliance project for Health and Trackers division (formerly Fitbit) focusing on DMA 5(2) and the German Federal Cartel Office (FCO).
- Delivered the project successfully with cross-functional teams, ensuring timely delivery and zero privacy issues.
- Achieved compliance with EU Commission regulations while managing a team and ensuring smooth communication across departments.
- Ensured compliance with stringent data privacy and legal frameworks, meeting all deadlines.

COHERENT SOLUTIONS, INC. | SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER Apr 2019 – Aug 2023 | Belarus - Türkiye

- Managed a team of 4 engineers, collaborating with cross-functional teams to design and implement cross-service features.
- Took ownership of 7 different core business services including order-building, financial reporting, and user-notification services.
- Migrated ElasticSearch production live cluster from version 2.11 to 6.7 without downtime.
- Redesigned service architecture, reducing load on downstream services by 80 percent and optimizing computing resources.
- Designed and implemented an internal tool to improve E2E testing, increasing test coverage.

WIMIX LLC | SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Feb 2017 - Apr 2019 | Belarus

- Designed and developed a fintech trading robot that interacts with stock exchanges to calculate profitable investments.
- Participated in CI/CD processes, continuously monitoring system performance and improving stability.
- Implemented security measures to protect software and user data.
- Communicated with the customer and managed project roadmaps.

APPSHIRE LLC | Software Engineer

Feb 2016 - Feb 2017 | Belarus

- Developed a web application for managing large networks in real-time in hospitals and schools.
- Debugged and fixed issues while implementing changes to existing systems.
- Worked across web, mobile, and desktop applications, providing full-stack solutions.

ENGINEERING SECURITY SYSTEMS LLC | SOFTWARE

ENGINEER

Feb 2016 - Aug 2017 | Belarus

- Designed and developed a project for prediction of the temperature of the fire in a room, with possibility to generate visual graphs and reports.
- Created Web UI for the application.
- Performed technical support and maintenance for the local network.

SUMMARY

Senior Software Engineer with 8+ years of experience in designing, developing, and implementing complex software applications. Passionate about writing clean, maintainable code and designing elegant software solutions that adhere to best practices and industry standards. Experienced in leading teams, managing projects, and collaborating across functions to deliver successful software projects.

EDUCATION

BACHELOR'S DEGREE, SOFTWARE ENGINEER Belarusian State University of Informatics and Radioelectronics Faculty of Computer Technologies

SKILLS

PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES

Java • Groovy • Scala • Python • JavaScript

FRAMEWORKS & LIBRARIES

Spring Framework • Guice • Hibernate

DATABASES

SQL • MongoDB • Cassandra • ElasticSearch

CLOUD & DEVOPS TOOLS

AWS • Docker • Jenkins • Gradle • Git

OTHER METHODOLOGIES

CI/CD • Microservices • Agile

PERSONAL

LANGUAGES

English • Russian

LOCATION

Poland (EU)

LINKS

GitHub LinkedIn